Monochrome Inverted
本字幕由幻之×諸神×TVBT製作僅供試看使用不得將本片用於商業用途請與下載24小時之內刪除
如果您喜歡本作品請支援購買正版一切利用本片進行商業違法的行為與字幕組無關
翻譯:花澤かな、馬爺　校對:花澤かな、zwx　時軸:斷弦、醬子、小病　片源:MGRT　壓制:VCB-Sudio
Scarstory
Iron-blooded Chapter
March 25th
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
えっと
Um...
み…見てないよ
I didn't see anything.
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
なんて言うかさ
I've been thinking, y'know,
見られたくないものを隠すにしては
that skirts are totally unfit for
hiding things you don't want seen.
スカートって　どう考えてもセキュリティ低いよね
やっぱり　スパッツっていうファイアウォールが必要なのかな
A pair of  spats could serve as a firewall,
don't you think?
さ…さあ
Dunno.
If you'd excuse me.
じゃあ　僕はこれで
Wait a second!
ちょっと待ってよ
You walk so fast.
やっと追いついた　歩くの速いんだね
I could hardly catch up to you,
Araragi-kun.
阿良々木君
Araragi
何で僕の名前を知ってるの？
How do you know my name?
Eh? How couldn't I?
そりゃ知ってるよ　同じ学校じゃない
We go to the same school.
こざとへんに可能の可
Written with the 'a' from 'kanou'.
TL Note: Kanou means Possibility
Kanou
良い子の良いを二つ重ねて　樹木の木と書いて　阿良々木君
Two 'ra's from the first character in "ii ko"
TL Note: Ii ko means Good Kid
ra
ra        ra
And then the 'gi',
ra
the last character from "jumoku", Araragi-kun.
下の名前は年月の暦で暦　だよね
And your first name is
the word for calendar, "koyomi", right?
Koyomi
Thus we have Araragi Koyomi-kun.
だから阿良々木暦君
Araragi Koyomi
お前は…　羽川だ　羽川翼だ
You're Hanekawa, right?
Hanekawa Tsubasa.
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Wow.
Amazing! You know the name of someone like me!
すごい　私なんかの名前　知ってるなんて
二年生一学期の期末テストで
For our second-year finals, in the first semester,
保健体育及び芸術科目まで含めた全教科で
in all subjects,
physical education and visual arts included,
you got only one question wrong in the forms.
穴埋め問題一問しか間違わなかった　羽川翼
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Eh? Hey, come on, now!
ちょっと…　やだもう　なんでそんなことまで知ってるの？
Why do you know that much?
ひょっとして阿良々木君って　私のストーカーだったりする？
Araragi-kun, Could it be that you're...
my personal stalker?
Ahaha...
それはいくらなんでも被害妄想強すぎかな
Or maybe I'm just too paranoid.
別に
Not really.
宇宙人の友達に聞いたんだよ
My alien friend told me.
Wait, you've got friends?!
阿良々木くん　友達いるの？
Why are aliens more believable?!
宇宙人がいるかどうかを先にきけ
I didn't mean it like that.
いや　その　阿良々木くんって　いつも一人で
It's just that you seem to prefer being alone,
孤高に暮らしているみたいなイメージがあったから
like a hermit or something.
Well, you're right. I've got no friends.
まあ　友達がいないのはお前の言うとおりだ
But you're so famous that even
そんな友達がいない奴にも知られているほど
a loner like me knows about you.
お前は有名人だってことだよ
Stop that.
ちょっと　やめてよ
Jokes like that aren't funny to me.
そういう冗談はあまり好きじゃないの
ねえ　阿良々木君
Say, Araragi-kun.
阿良々木君は　吸血鬼って信じる？
Do you believe in vampires?
Vampires? What about them?
吸血鬼が　どうかしたのか
最近ね　ちょっとした噂になってるんだけど
I've been hearing some rumors lately...
...about a vampire being in town.
今　この町に吸血鬼がいるって
They say you shouldn't stay out alone at night.
だから夜とか　一人で出歩いちゃ駄目だって
That's a bit vague, sounds like a baseless rumor.
曖昧な　しかも信憑性のない噂だな
金髪の　すごく綺麗な女の人で
They say it's a beautiful blonde-haired woman,
with eyes so cold they chill you to the bone.
背筋が凍るくらい　冷たい眼をした吸血鬼なんだってさ
And that makes her a vampire?
それだけじゃ　吸血鬼だってわからないだろ
金髪だから目立ってるだけの　一般人じゃないのか
Couldn't it just be a normal human being
who stands out because they're blonde?
でも
But... I've heard that under the streetlights,
街灯に照らされて　金髪は眩しいくらいだったのに
her blonde hair almost shines,
yet she has no shadow.
影がなかったって
しかし　まあ夜のことだし
Still, this happened at night.
街灯に照らされていたと言っても　見間違いということもあるだろう
It's not like streetlights
make shadows unmistakably clear.
Yeah, I think it's a silly rumor too.
馬鹿馬鹿しい噂だと　私も思う
But...
でも　私はね　吸血鬼がいるなら　会ってみたいって思うのよ
if there was actually a vampire,
I'd love to meet them.
そういう　人よりも上位の存在みたいなのが　いたらいいなって
I'm intrigued by such superhuman creatures.
人より上位って　神様とかか
By superhuman, do you mean something like a god?
別に神様じゃなくてもいいんだけど
It doesn't have to be a god.
でないと　色々報われないじゃない
It wouldn't be worth the trouble otherwise.
My bad, my bad.
いけない　いけない
You're so easy to chat with.
阿良々木くん　意外と話しやすい人なんだね
So easy...
口が滑って　ちょっとわけのわからないことを言っちゃったような気がするよ
I feel like I said stuff that doesn't make much sense.
You're so fun to talk to, Araragi-kun.
こんな話しやすい阿良々木くんに　友達がいないなんて　おかしいね
It's weird you've got no friends.
Why don't you make friends?
何で友達　作らないの？
If I made friends, I'd lower my power as a human.
友達を作ると　人間強度が下がるから
What?
Sorry, I'm not really following what you said.
ごめん　ちょっと意味がわからない
I really don't know how to word it.
いや　だから　なんかこう　だな
友達がいたら　友達のことを気にしなくちゃいけないだろ
If I had friends, I'd have to care about them.
友達が傷ついたら　自分も傷ついちゃうし
If they got hurt, I'd be hurt too.
友達が悲しいと自分も悲しい
If they were sad, I'd be sad too.
言ってみれば弱点が増えるってことだと思う
Putting it that way, these weak points build up.
And I'd grow even weaker as a person.
それは人間としての弱体化だ
But when your friends have fun, you'd have fun too.
けど　友達が楽しんでいたら自分も楽しいし
友達が嬉しいと自分も嬉しいんだから
When they're happy, you'd be happy too.
It doesn't necessarily have to be a weakness.
一概に弱くなってるわけじゃないんじゃないの？
No.
いや　友達が楽しんでいると羨ましいし
My friends having fun would make me jealous.
A friend's happiness would just make me envious.
友達が嬉しいと妬ましい
What a petty person you are.
人間が小さい
ほっとけや
Give me a break.
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
私
I'm...
Hmm?
これから図書館に行こうと思うんだけど
I'm going to head to the library now.
阿良々木くんも一緒に行く？
Wanna come along, Araragi-kun?
Why?
なんで　図書館で何するんだよ
What would I do in a library?
Study, of course.
そりゃ　勉強でしょう
そりゃって
Of course?
生憎　僕は宿題もない春休みに　わざわざ自主的に勉強するほど
Sorry, but even without homework to do on break,
I'm not praiseworthy enough to study on my own.
奇特じゃないんだ
But...
でも　来年はもう受験生だよ
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
next semester
you'll have to prepare for university entry exams.
University?
受験も何も　僕は卒業さえ危ぶまれてるんだ
I'll be happy if I can graduate at all.
I'm not gonna make it, no matter what I do.
もう何したって間に合わないよ
阿良々木くん　携帯持ってる？
Araragi-kun, Do you have a cell phone?
Uh, yeah?
そりゃ　携帯くらいは
Gimme.
貸して
Thanks. Here.
ありがと　はい　返す
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
私の番号とメルアド　登録しといたから
I added my number and email.
Hanekawa Tsubasa
ざーんねん　友達　できちゃったね
Too bad!
Looks like you've just made a friend!
なんだあいつ？
What's wrong with her?
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Naoetsu
Private
High
School
Entrance
Flashback
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Naoetsu North
Express
Local
Departures
Platform
Naoetsu Central
Naoetsu South
Shinjuku
Ginza
Oizumi-gakuen
New York
Perfect,
うぬ…
儂を　助けさせてやる
you shall help me.
聞こえんのか
Can you not hear me?
儂を助けさせてやると　そう言うておるのじゃ
I said you shall help me.
Hey...
お…おい
Are you okay?
お前　大丈夫なのか
す…すぐに　救急車を…
I'll get you an ambulance!
きゅうきゅうしゃ？　そんなものはいらんわ
Ambulance?
There's no need for such a thing.
じゃから　うぬの血を寄越せ
Give me...
thine blood.
Do you believe in vampires?
阿良々木君は吸血鬼って信じる？
金髪の　すごく綺麗な女の人で
They say it's a beautiful blonde-haired woman,
with eyes so cold they chill you to the bone.
背筋が凍るくらい　冷たい眼をした吸血鬼なんだってさ
I am Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade,
我が名は　キスショット・アセロラオリオン・ハートアンダーブレード
鉄血にして熱血にして冷血の吸血鬼じゃ
The Iron-blooded,
Hot-blooded,
Cold-blooded vampire.
うぬの血を　我が肉として呑み込んでやろう
I shall take ye as my own flesh.
Therefore, I demand thine blood.
じゃから　うぬの血を寄越せ
I thought vampires...
吸血鬼ってのは　不死身のはずじゃ　ないのかよ
were immortal.
Was I wrong?
I lost too much blood.
血を失い過ぎた　もはや再生もできぬ　変形もできぬ
Too much to even regenerate or transform.
このままでは　死んでしまう
I am about to die.
取るに足らん人間ごときが　我が血肉となれることを光栄に思え
As a lowly human,
thou should consider becoming my flesh
to be a great honor.
Blood?
血…血って　輸血とかじゃ　駄目なのか
Can't you get a transfusion or something?
ど…どれくらい　いるんだよ
How much do you need?
とりあえず　うぬ一人分もらえれば
Everything you have should keep me alive for now.
急場は凌げる
I see. All I've got.
そうか　僕一人分…
どうした　血を…血を寄越せ　早く…
What's wrong?
I demand your blood!
Now! Hurry!
早くするのじゃ
早くするのじゃ　こののろまが
Hurry, you fool!
大丈夫　逃げられるはずだ
It's fine.
I can get away.
こんな栄誉が　ほかにあるのと思うのか
Can you imagine any honor greater than this?
I can get away from this.
逃げ切れるはずだ
Just run.
That will let me
escape this reality.
おい
Hey,
you're kidding, right?
う…嘘じゃろう
You refuse to help me?!
助けて…　くれんのか
No!
嫌だ　嫌　嫌だ　嫌だ
No! No! I don't wanna die!
死にたくない　死にたくない　死にたくない
I don't wanna die! I don't wanna die!
助けて　助けて　お願い
Help me! Help me, please!
Please, I beg you!
お願…お願いします
Help me...
嫌だ　嫌だ
No!
ごめんなさい　ごめんなさい　ごめんなさい　ごめんなさい
I'm sorry!
ごめんなさい　ごめんなさい
I would die.
自分が死ぬんだ
She's a monster!
そうでなくとも化物だ
A vampire!
吸血鬼なんだ
助ける必要はない
I don't have to help her.
Right?
そうだろう
I know, goddamn it!
わかってんだよ　そんなことは
Don't give up, you moron!
諦めんな　馬鹿
い…いいの？
Are you sure?
Of course I'm not.
悪いに決まってんだろうが　この野郎
畜生　畜生　畜生
Damn it.
Why?
なんで　どうしてこんなことになったんだ
How did it come to this?
I swear I'll do better in my next life.
次の人生じゃ　絶対にうまくやる
I'll be smart,
要領のいい　嫌なことは全部他人のせいにできる
and everything bad that happens
will be everyone else's fault.
そんな人間に生まれ変わってやる　だから
That's the type of person I'll be.
So... I'll help you.
僕がお前を助けてやる　僕の血を吸え
Take my blood.
I give it all to you.
全部やる　一滴残らず　絞り尽くせ
Every last drop of it.
Don't leave anything.
ありがとう
Thank you.
Was it a dream?
夢？
Surprise
Hey!
お…おい　お…起きろ
Wake up.
Just five more minutes.
あと五分
Five minutes
Wake up already!
だ…だから起きろって
あと気分
Not feeling it right now.
Feeling it
How long are you gonna sleep?!
どれだけ寝る気だよ
四十六億年くらい
4.6 billion years
Like 4.6 billion years.
地球がもう一個できちゃうよ
That's enough to create Earth all over again!
March 28th
It's been two days?
あれから二日も経ってるのか
Fool!
たわけ
Good grief.
まったく
How stupid do you have to be...
いきなり太陽の下に出る馬鹿がどこにおるのじゃ
to jump right into the sunlight?
並の吸血鬼なら　一瞬で蒸発しておったぞ
Any regular vampire would burn in an instant.
日のある内は二度と外に出るでないぞ
Never go outside while the sun is up.
なまじ不死力があるだけに
You are immortal,
焼かれ　回復し　焼かれ　回復しの　永遠の繰り返しじゃ
so you would burn and regenerate,
and burn and regenerate forever.
Well, that is if you consider vampires
まあ　不死の吸血鬼を生きておるのだと定義すればじゃがのう
to be alive in the first place.
Vampire?
きゅうけつ…き
Wait, then, are you...
じゃあ　お前　ひょっとして
Flashback
うん　いかにも　キスショット・アセロラオリオン・ハートアンダーブレードじゃ
'Tis I, Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade.
ハートアンダーブレードと呼ぶがよい
Call me Heart-under-blade.
眷属を造るのは四百年ぶり
It has been 400 years since I made my last kin.
You are my second.
二回目じゃったが　まあその回復力を見る限りにおいて
Seeing your regeneration earlier,
うまくいったようじゃな
I'd call it a great success.
Kin?
け…眷属
Kin
そう　ゆえに　うぬ…
Indeed! Therefore you—
そう言えば　まだうぬの名前を聞いておらんかったの
That reminds me. I have yet to get your name.
Well, it doesn't matter.
まあよいか
The name you bore once before
これまでの名前など　今のうぬにとっては何の意味も持たん
is meaningless hereafter.
ともかく　従僕よ
Well, my servant,
welcome to the world of the night.
ようこそ　夜の世界へ
Where...
Where are we?
ここはどこなんだ？
I believe it was called a cram school.
確か　「塾」と言うものらしいぞ
It went bankrupt a few years ago
数年前に潰れたようじゃが
and is abandoned now.
今はただの廃墟じゃ
A suitable place to withdraw to.
この通り　身を潜めるには便利じゃな
じゃあ　キスショット　次の質問だけど
Then Kiss-shot, Next question.
Hold it!
待てい
I told you to call me Heart-under-blade, did I not!
儂のことはハートアンダーブレードと呼べと言ったじゃろう
That's way too long.
長ったらしいだろうが
キスショットのほうが短くていい
I prefer Kiss-shot. It's short.
それとも　そう呼んじゃいけないのか
Can't I call you that?
Oh well.
いや　まあ　そうじゃな
If you prefer it, so shall it be.
うぬがそれでよいのならばそれでよいじゃろう
I have no reason to forbid it.
断る理由もないわ
So?
それで　次の質問とは何じゃ？
What is your next question?
I turned into a vampire, right?
えっと　僕は吸血鬼に　なったんだよな
Is it not obvious?
当たり前じゃ
Do I need to spell it out for you?
今更説明するまでもあるまい
You became my kin, my servant.
うぬは儂の眷属となり　従僕となったのじゃ
Consider it an honor.
光栄に思え
従僕って
Your servant...
じゃあ　どうしてお前　そんな子供みたいな身体つきになってんだ
Why do you have a child's body now?
会ったときのお前は　もっとこう…
Earlier you were more...
mature—
大人っぽくて
子供っぽくて悪かったのう
Sorry for not being more "mature"!
That's not what I meant.
いや　そうじゃなくて
Mature
And
Your limbs were severed
I took all your blood,
うぬの血は　絞り尽くしたがの
それでは全然足りなかったのじゃ
but it was insufficient.
Therefore I took a form I could sustain.
じゃからそれ相応の姿になっておる
Still better than perishing.
これでも死なぬだけマシじゃ
とは言え　最低限の不死身しか保てぬし
Then again,
I can only sustain a minimum
amount of immortality,
吸血鬼としての能力のほとんどが制限されておる
and most of my vampire powers
are unavailable now.
Inconvenient indeed.
不便極まりないな
Flashback
手足もこの通り
My limbs are restored, as you can see.
形だけでも再生できたしのう
まあ　中身はスカスカなのじゃが
I could regenerate the form, but not the power.
とは言え　当面はこれで大丈夫じゃ
This should suffice for now.
That said, do not forget that you are my servant.
しかしな　そうは言っても上下関係はきっちりしておくぞ
従僕
I may look this way now,
こんなナリになっておっても　儂は五百年から生きておる吸血鬼じゃ
but I am a vampire who has lived for five centuries.
You are but a newborn as a vampire.
吸血鬼としては生まれたてのうぬが
本来ならば対等に口を利ける相手ではないのじゃぞ
Know your place when you address me.
...sure.
What? Make your replies clear.
なんじゃ
曖昧な返事じゃの
Do you really understand?
本当にわかっておるのか
I do...
まあ　わかるけど
ならば服従の証として　儂の頭を撫でてみよ
Then as a sign of your obedience, pat my head.
That should do.
まあ　よかろう
Why did you turn me into a vampire?
どうして　僕を吸血鬼にした？
I was prepared to die being drained by you.
僕はお前に　吸い尽くされ　殺される覚悟だったんだけど
I did not intend to.
別に　したくてしたわけではない
All who have their blood drunk by a vampire will,
吸血鬼に血を吸われれば　例外なく誰もが吸血鬼と化す
without exception, turn into vampires.
That is all.
それだけのことじゃ
I see...
そう　なのか
It is quite convenient for me.
まあ　それは儂にとっては都合のよいことよ
There is something I need you to do.
うぬには　やってもらわねばならんことがあるからじゃ
Your blood alone
うぬ一人の血では　ここまでしか身体を回復できんかった
only allows me to regenerate so much.
I am far from my full potential.
今の儂はフルパワーからは程遠い
Which is why you shall act in my stead.
じゃからこの先は　うぬに動いてもらわぬといかん
What do you want from me?
僕に何を？
Can I...
僕は
...return to being human?
人間に戻れるのか
I thought so.
やはり
そうじゃろうなあ
I was prepared for that question.
そう言い出すと思っておったの
So? Can I?!
で　どうなんだよ　僕は
You can.
戻れるよ
I can guarantee that.
保証するよ
I give you my word if needed.
儂の名にかけての
The names of three people who robbed Kiss-shot of parts of her body.
Those three are specialist vampire slayers.
その三名は吸血鬼退治を専門としておる者共じゃ
They're the ones that killed you?
で　そいつらに退治されたってことか
Are you out of your mind?
たわけたことを吐かすな
They have yet to finish me off.
まだされてはおらん
However, they took my limbs.
が　手足を奪われたのは痛い
I have very little regenerative power left too.
回復力もほとんど残っておらんし
I have no chance of standing against them now.
今のこの状態では　戦いようもない
So...
だから
...you shall face those three and take back my limbs.
うぬがその三名と渡り合って
儂の手足を取り戻してきてくれればよいのじゃ
Huh?
よ…よいのじゃって…
"You shall" as if it was that simple.
そんな簡単に
To make you human once again,
うぬを人間に戻すためには　儂はフルパワーの状態に戻らねばならんのじゃ
I must regain my full power.
I must be whole again.
言ってみれば完全体にな
My limbs are absolutely necessary for that.
そのためには　あの手足は絶対に必要なのじゃ
で…でも　僕　戦うとか普通に無理だぜ
But I can't fight at all.
Won't I just get slain instead?
最悪　僕が退治されちゃうんじゃないのか
Fool.
たわけ
You still think as if you were human.
それはうぬが人間であった頃の話じゃろうが
You are now my kin.
今のうぬは我が眷属じゃ
Now that I am weakened to a bare minimum,
最低レベルにまで弱体化している今現在なら
while I am still a top-class vampire,
吸血鬼としては最高ランクのこの儂を殺すことさえ容易じゃわ
you could still kill me.
So you're a weak vampire?
つまり　お前は吸血鬼として弱いほうだって話か
No!
違うわ
You're weakened,
まあ　弱体化しているお前より　今の僕のほうが強いとしても
so I might be stronger than you at this point,
but those three
その三人は　フルパワー　完全体の状態のお前から　手足を奪ったんだろ
managed to take your limbs
when you were at full power.
How could I—
だったら
I was at a disadvantage
三人がかりじゃったから不覚を取っただけじゃ
because they came at me at once.
I took them lightly.
侮っておった
What I mean is...
つまりじゃ　ひとりずつを相手にする限りにおいて
that as long as you take on them one by one,
その三人はうぬの敵ではないわ
they shall stand no chance against you.
Simply put: it is an easy task.
はっきり言って　楽な仕事じゃ
ど…どうすんだよ
What do I do?
Dismember
Would you at least hear me out?!
は…話し合おうとかしろよ　お前ら
Dismember
I'm human!
ぼ…僕は人間なんだぞ
Do you want to murder a fellow human?!
お前ら
人殺しをする気か
Mur
der
Spin
You seem so worked up.
本当君たちは　元気いいなあ
Did something nice happen to you?
何かいいことでも　あったのかい
Huh?
あれ？
Thanks for saving me.
ありがとう
助かった
No need for thanks.
礼なんていいよ
You got saved on your own,
きみが一人で助かっただけさ
Araragi-kun.
阿良々木くん
Don't be so alarmed.
そう警戒するなよ
Your stare's sharp.
そんなぎらぎらした眼ェしちゃってさ
You seem so worked up.
元気いいなあ
Did something nice happen to you?
何かいいことでもあったのかい
Let's just go home for now, Araragi-kun.
まあ　とりあえず帰ろうぜ
阿良々木くん
Home?
帰ろうって
To that old abandoned cram school.
あの学習塾跡の廃墟だよ
Huh?
Hold on a second!
ちょっと待てよ
How do you know about that?
な…なんでそんなこと知ってんだ
Why are you surprised?
そりゃ知ってるよ
I'm the one who told her about it.
何せ　あの子にあの場所を教えたのは僕なんだからね
Failing to do the right thing is the sign of cowardice.
まあ　義を見てせざるは勇なきなりってね
That girl, Heart-under-blade,
あの子　ハートアンダーブレードが
きみの身体を引きずって随分困っていたみたいだからさ
looked like she was in trouble,
dragging your body around,
so I gave her a good spot.
いい場所を教えてあげたんだ
Who are you?
お前は…　何者なんだ
I'm just an old man who happened to pass by.
僕はただの通りすがりのおっさんだよ
Don't worry.
安心しなよ
I'm no vampire slayer or specialist.
僕は吸血鬼退治の専門家とかじゃないからさ
I practice in a much wider field.
僕の専門はもっと広い
手広くやらせてもらっているのさ
I'll introduce myself properly later.
まあ　自己紹介はあとでさせてもらうよ
You're back!
帰ったか
Who is that behind you?
後ろの奴は　見覚えがあるな
I feel like I've met you before.
That's so mean.
酷いなあ
Is that all you remember of me?
その程度の認識かよ
So?
それで　首尾はどうじゃった？
How did it go?
This is a problem.
参ったのう
Those three are still working together.
あの三人　まだつるんでおるのか
They took you out...
とにかく　お前のフルパワーモードでも三人がかりじゃやられちまったんだろ
...even at your full power.
I stand no chance against them.
だったら　僕があの三人に勝てるわけがないだろう
Which is why I told you to take them on one by one!
じゃから　一人ずつなら
They're together. It's not happening.
つるんでるんじゃ　それも無理だろ
You said we could just lay low,
お前は大人しくしてりゃ大丈夫だって言ってたけど
but who knows when they find us he—
ここだって　いつ突き止められるか
それについては問題ないよ
no need to worry about that.
I drew up a boundary around here
ここには　きみ達が眠ってる間に
while you were asleep.
こっそりと結界を張っておいてあげたからさ
A boundary?
結界
Like a barrier?
バリアみたいなもんか
Something like that.
まっ　そんなようなもんだ
What's up with you, exactly?
お前　どういうつもりなんだ
Why did you help Kiss-shot and me?
どうしてキスショットを
僕らを助けるんだ
I realize you're not an enemy,
敵じゃないことはわかってきたけれど
but I doubt you're on our side.
僕にはお前が　味方だとは思えないのに
Jeez, you're so cruel.
酷いことを言うなあ
全く
I'm maintaining the balance.
僕はね　バランスを取っているんだよ
Consider that my job.
言うなら　それが僕の仕事なのさ
I bridge this side and the other.
こちらとあちらの橋渡し
Introduce yourself.
自己紹介しろよ
You said you would.
後でするって言ったろ
Spin
Oshino Meme.
忍野メメ
Oshino Meme
I'm like a rolling stone.
住所不定の自由人さ
I'm kind of an authority on
まあ　妖怪変化のオーソリティだと思ってくれりゃいい
monsters and apparitions.
Unlike those three,
あの三人と違って
I'm not great at exorcism though.
妖怪退治ってのは　あんまり得意じゃないけどね
Not great?
得意じゃないって
Let me rephrase that.
もう少しありていに言うと
I don't like it.
好きじゃないんだよね
Doesn't that make you a specialist then?
でも　専門じゃないのかよ
Maintaining the balance is my specialty.
専門は　だからバランスを取ること
I negotiate from neutral ground.
中立の立ち位置で
ネゴシエーションすること
Call me a mediator.
まあ　強いて言うなら交渉人だよ
Negotiation?
交渉？
Bridging this side and the other?
こちらとあちらの　橋渡し
Where is "this side" and where's "the other"?
こちらとはどこで
あちらとはどこだ
Speech / Voice
Are the two sides humans and monsters?
こちらは人間で
あちらは化物か
In that case, which side
do I belong to?
Monsters?
化物
That's good.
いいね
I prefer to call them oddities though.
僕は怪異と呼んでいるが
Oddity
And she's the oddity slayer.
そしてその子は怪異殺しと呼ばれている
She's a rare kind of vampire
怪異からエナジードレインできる
who can drain energy from oddities.
珍しいタイプの吸血鬼だ
That makes her pretty famous actually.
まあ　だからこそ有名な子なんだよね
I listened to your little chat earlier.
さっきの君達の話し合いを　なんとなく聞かせてもらっていたげれど
Quite the pinch you're in.
結構大変な事態になってるみたいじゃない
I didn't expect things to take such a difficult turn.
まさかこんなにややこしいことが起こるとはね
There is nothing difficult about it.
ややこしくなどない
It is extremely simple.
至極簡単じゃ
In the eyes of an undying vampire, maybe.
長命の吸血鬼のスパンで見れば　そうなんだろうけどねえ
It's quite the trouble for us humans.
僕ら人間としては困ったもんだよ
Right, Araragi-kun?
ねえ　阿良々木くん
Also, Heart-under-blade,
それに　僕は気に入ったよ　ハートアンダーブレード
I liked how you agreed to return your kin,
眷属とした阿良々木くんを　ちゃんと人間に戻してあげようというきみの心意気にね
Araragi-kun, to being human.
Should I mediate for you?
何なら　僕が間に立ってあげてもいいよ
Between us and those three?
間に立つって
あの三人との間？
Who else?
他にないだろ
So you'll help us?
た…助けて　くれるってことか
No. But I'll lend you a hand.
助けない　力を貸すだけ
The balance feels off as it is right now.
今のままじゃ　やっぱりちょっと　バランスが悪いような気もするからね
It's like I'm watching bullies get their way.
これじゃあいじめみたいなもんだ
Of course,
でももちろん　僕も仕事だから
since it's my job,
I'm not gonna do it for free.
ただってわけにはいかないよ
How about...
そうだな
2 million Yen?
二百万くらいでどう？
2 million?!
に…にひゃく
Akasegawa
You pay when you can,
あるとき払いの催促なしだ
and I won't bother you about it.
That much is the least I must ask
それくらいは要求しないと
to maintain the balance.
それはそれでバランスが取れないものでね
But...
で…でも
Shall we hear your exact plan?
具体的なプランを聞こうかの
Negotiations sound nice, but it is not so easy.
交渉と言っても　容易ではあるまい
Trying to convince those three is futile.
あの三人を説得することなどできぬぞ
All I can do is ask...
僕にできることは　頭を下げてお願いするだけさ
...earnestly.
誠意を込めてね
If begging doesn't work,
お願いできないのなら危険思想に手を出すしかないけれど
more dangerous ideas get involved.
If we can at least communicate, we can play a game.
幸い　言葉が通じるのなら
ゲームができる
A game?
ゲーム　じゃと？
Firstly, we need to separate them.
まずは　あの三人をバラかすのが先だろうね
You said dealing with them
ひとりひとりを相手にすれば　問題ないってのが
one by one shouldn't be an issue.
ハートアンダーブレード　きみの読みなんだろう
We should make that happen then.
なら　それを実現させようじゃないか
Boy, how do you
しかしのう　小僧よ
plan to negotiate with them in the first place?
あの三人とどうやって交渉するのじゃ？
The details are a trade secret.
詳しくは企業秘密だけど
I'll level the playing field,
フィールドは僕が整えてあげよう
and Araragi-kun can get back your limbs.
そして阿良々木くんが　彼らから手足を取り戻す
If you regain your limbs,
無事に両腕両脚を取り戻せば
you also regain your full power,
ハートアンダーブレードはパワーを回復できて
which means you can return Araragi-kun to human.
そうすれば　阿良々木くんは無事に人間に戻れるというわけだ
Servant!
おい　従僕
I cannot procure human money.
儂は人間の貨幣は用意できん
I have no idea how heavy a debt of 2 million Yen is.
二百万円という借金がどの程度のものなのかもよくわからんが
Can you shoulder it?
その金額をうぬは背負うことができるか
Do not worry.
心配するな
His skills are real.
この小僧のスキルは本物じゃ
I may be weak now, but even I can see that.
いかに弱体化しても　それくらいのことはわかる
I don't have that much saved,
そんな貯金はねえけど
but if I get to pay when I can,
あるとき払いの催促なし
and I don't need collateral or a guarantor,
ついでに保証人も担保もいらないって言うんだったら
then I'll shoulder it.
僕が背負うよ
Deal then.
じゃ　決まり
Thanks for your patronage.
まいどあり
Just kidding.
なんつって
Voice only
Kiss-shot Acerola-orion Heart-under-blade
Eye for an eye, tooth for a tooth...
目には目　歯には歯
Iron-blooded, Hot-blooded, and Cold-blooded
吸血鬼には吸血鬼　じゃ
...vampire for a vampire.
Red
Unnumbered Scene
Vampire
Voice only
Dramaturgy
Let us begin then.
それでは始めるとしよう
A giant of over 2 meters.
A dual wielder, he held
rippled, huge swords in
both his hands. Such
swords are commonly
referred to as flamberge.
He was a goliath, a man of
massive muscles. He wore
a headband to comb up his
unruly hair. He is the
vampire slayer that took
Kiss-shot's right arm.
(omitted)
It was March 31st,
the last day of March.
A giant of over 2 meters.
A dual wielder, he held
rippled, huge swords in
both his hands. Such
swords are commonly
referred to as flamberge.
He was a goliath, a man of
massive muscles. He wore
a headband to comb up his
unruly hair. He is the
vampire slayer that took
Kiss-shot's right arm.
(omitted)
It was March 31st,
the last day of March.
A kin-slayer vampire
Voice only
Episode
That's Hilarious!
超ウケる
He wore a white cloak and had cunning eyes.
He lifted a gargantuan cross three times his size and more
than three times his weight to his shoulder with one hand.
He wore a white cloak and had cunning eyes.
He lifted a gargantuan cross three times his size and more
than three times his weight to his shoulder with one hand.
He is a vampire hunter. He hunts vampires for the prize on their heads.
That makes him a bounty hunter. And furthermore—
Half    ampire
v
Voice only
Guillotine Cutter
不愉快ですね
So unpleasant.
He resembled a priest, with hair that would rival the back of a hedgehog.
He might even seem gentle at first impression.
Human
A human who denies the existence of oddities.
A human who erases the existence of oddities.
Araragi-kun!
阿良々木くん　私に構わないで
Voice only
Hanekawa Tsubasa
Don't worry about me!
He's a nice guy, but that's not all.
He's strong.
構わないわけないだろうが
Voice only
As if I could do that!
Araragi Koyomi
That was the first time
If I can't see you ever again,
お前にも会えないんだったら
人間に戻ったってなんの意味もないんだよ
I felt like I finally met Hanekawa for real.
there's no point in being a human again at all!
No mistakes. Straight, eye to eye.
Araragi-kun.
阿良々木君
Preview
人間であることを諦めろ
Give up being human.
Scarstory
Hot-blooded Chapter
In theaters nationwide summer 2016
Scarstory
Hot-blooded Chapter
In theaters nationwide summer 2016